## **Rinat Sabitov**

- Kazan, Russia
- +7 927 491 99 67
- rinat.sabitov@gmail.com
- https://false.org.ru

Briefly about me. I've been doing web development in Python for more than 7 years. I am a server-side guy but I also know how client-side stuff works. I am one of the founders and organizers of DevDay IT community in Kazan city. I make some contribution into OpenStack Liberty. I'm a maintainer of commonly use python library for a CouchDB

#### Education

Master's degree, Kazan State Technical University named after A. N. Tupolev, 2004 – 2009 automated-systems, software-engineering

Specialization: computer and automatic systems software

#### $\mathbf{Also}$

- reserve-officer training department (signaller)
- radio amateur licence (CEPT NOVICE)

# Work Experience

**Python Developer**, Cloud Linux Kernelcare, May 2018 - Current [Remote] python, jenkins, grafana, graphite, clickhouse, ansible, InfluxDB, telegraf

### Progress:

- Log analysing tools
- Third party products intergrations
- Participating in a python developers grading comitee

Python Developer, Cloud Linux Kuberdock, March 2016 - May 2018 [Remote]

python, kubernetes, docker, ansible, ceph, redis, twisted, amazon-web-services, buildbot, packer, jenkins, golang Progress:

- Implemented developer environment deployment scripts
- Complex backup scripts
- Gradual upgrade system from scratch
- Maintaining a distributed linux packages build system.
- Automated images build system (AWS, OpenNebula, Vagrant, and others)
- Holding technical interviews python developers

Python Developer, ASD Technologies, June 2015 - March 2016

openstack, ansible, docker, python, amqp, rabbitmq, amazon-web-services, fuse, celery

#### Progress:

- Applying OpenStack Mistral component for internal usage.
- Writing instances backup workflow scripts using YAQL.
- Writing dashboards for OpenStack Horizon covering mistral component API.
- Writing devstack deploying scripts for the vagrant.
- Deploying openstack components on docker with ansible.
- Applying AMQP realizations for systems components interoperability.
- $\bullet~$  FUSE implementation for caching some disk operations.

## Senior Developer, BARS Group, November 2010 - May 2015

python, django, scrum, extjs4, celery, nginx, nsis, postgresql, soap, xml, architecture

Full life circle django RIA development. Participating in several high-load projects for a government (The Ministry of Education) as maintainer and development from scratch. I led the development department. First attempts to implement Agile methodology and code review. Tried to get more points in the Joel test (8 so far).

#### Progress:

- integration with Russian E-Government infrastructures (Unified system of interagency electronic interaction)
- complex b2b integrations, SOAP services and authorization backends
- streamlined continuous integration process
- code review
- more than 80% tests coverage
- $\bullet\,$  complex business logic and reporting server-side implementation
- writing simple ExtJS based user interfaces
- implemented a continuous integration for most of our projects
- written some new components for our platform.

#### Also:

- internal training and tutorials
- participating in technical interviews with candidates and staff certification

Developer, AkBarsMed, August 2009 – November 2010

delphi, intraweb, firebird

For several years I worked in the health insurance sector, where developed accounting and information systems. One of these systems serving a population of one state (~3M people). Client-server architecture with Firebird DB server on one side (1000+ stored procedures), and Delphi client on other.

#### Progress:

- first version control (Subversion) for source code implementation in the department
- first web-applications in the department
- massive refactoring + migrating from Delphi 5 to Delphi 7
- fuzzy mailing addresses recognition based on soundex

# Certifications

Functional Programming Principles in Scala (Coursera), 2014 - 2014

## **Projects**

- py-couchdb python, https://github.com/histrio/py-couchdb Modern pure python CouchDB Client.
- czfrq python, rust, https://github.com/histrio/czfrq Generate anki deck from Czech frequency word list
- $\bullet \ \mathbf{rssbook} \ \mathbf{-go}, \ \mathbf{https://github.com/histrio/rssbook} \ \mathbf{Set} \ \mathbf{of} \ \mathbf{tools} \ \mathbf{that} \ \mathbf{helps} \ \mathbf{to} \ \mathbf{make} \ \mathbf{a} \ \mathbf{podcast} \ \mathbf{from} \ \mathbf{an} \ \mathbf{audiobook}.$
- python-descript-ion python, https://github.com/histrio/python-descript-ion Simple library for descript.ion files manipulation

## Also

secure conversation:

PGP: rinat.sabtiov@gmail.com 4096R/D122293D: 8A98 93D4 B64B 480E 471D BE57 1883 9067 D122 293D